The House of the Spirits is a romance, drama film directed by Bille August.
A rancher, his clairvoyant wife and their family
face turbulent years in South America.
Clara del Valle Trueba, played by Meryl Streep.
Ferula Trueba, played by Glenn Close.
Esteban Trueba, played by Jeremy Irons.
Blanca Trueba, played by Winona Ryder.
Pedro Tercero Gareia, played by Antonio Banderas.
Severo del Valle, played by Armin Mueller-Stahl.
The House of the Spirits (Danish: Åndernes hus) is a 1993 historical drama film written and directed by Bille August and
starring Jeremy Irons, Meryl Streep, Glenn Close, Winona Ryder, Antonio Banderas and Vanessa Redgrave.
The supporting cast includes María Conchita Alonso,
Armin Mueller-Stahl, and Jan Niklas.
Based on the 1982 novel by Isabel Allende, the film follows three generations of
women from a Chilean family during the country’s military dictatorship.
Although the film won several awards in Europe, including Best Film at the Lola Awards from the German Film Academy and the
Robert Award from the Danish Film Academy, in America it was regarded as a critical and commercial failure.
The film explores themes of farm, central and south america,
farm worker, paranormal phenomena, coup d'etat.
The tone is emotional.